https://sobe.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/fouzul-kabir-khan

Skip to content * DSpace * Library * Faculty Members * Degree Verification * Important Contact * Apply Online

• Profile Login

Search for: * Home * About * Admission * Programs Research * BBA * BBA in AIS * Economics * MBA * EMBA * MIHRM * MSc in Economics Home * Research Research * Journal Paper * Conference Paper * Faculty Members Research * Business Administration * Department of Economics * Students Research * UCAM * eLMS * Notice * Events * News * Notices * Contact

Dr. M. Fouzul Kabir Khan

Professor, School of Business & Economics (SoBE)

ROOM: 733 (A) PABX: 5126 Email: fouzul@bus.uiu.ac.bd * Home * Faculty Profiles

- Bio
- Work Experience
- Education

Bio

M. Fouzul Kabir Khan is an economist and finance professional with a career spanning academia, government, and the private sector. He was Secretary of Power, Government of Bangladesh. He was also the founder Chief Executive Officer of IDCOL (www.idcol.org). As CEO of IDCOL, he managed nearly half a billion dollar infrastructure finance fund provided by the World Bank. In the same capacity, he designed and implemented the most successful solar home systems (SHS) program in the world under which more than 4 million SHSs have been installed in rural Bangladesh. He has also taught for over 15 years as a professor of Economics at North South University's MBA program, as a Senior Fellow at National University of Singapore, instructor at University of Massachusetts at Boston, Visiting Professor (part-time) at BRAC University and East-West University. He has lectured/offered courses at National Defense College, Bangladesh Public Administration Training Complex, Foreign Service Academy, and for ADFIMI in Turkey, Azerbaijan, Singapore, Bali and other places. He has co-authored a book, Financing Large Projects, published by Perason/Prentice Hall, and has done extensive consulting work for the World Bank, ADB, IFC, UNDP, GtZ, and JICA in various countries.

Work Experience

Position: Secretary, Ministry of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources

Year: 2007-2009 Location: Dhaka

Institution: Ministry of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources, GoB Position: Chief Executive Officer

Year: Mar 1998 to June 2007 Location: Bangladesh

Institution: Infrastructure Development company Limited (IDCoL)/The world Bank Position: Senior Fellow (Senior Lecturer)

Year: 1992-1995 Location: Singapore

Institution: National University of Singapore Position: Instructor

Year: September 1985-June 1989

Location: USA

Institution: University of Massachusctts, Boston & Boston University

Education

- 1. Ph.D in Economics, Boston University, USA, 1989
- 2. M.A.P.E. Boston University, USA, 1987
- 3. B.A. Honours in Economics, Dhaka University, 1976

Follow Us

About UIU

- Why UIU
- Vision Mission Goals
- General Information
- UIU Campus
- Guiding Principles
- Ranking & Accreditation
- Convocation
- Gallery
- Media
- Career
- Contact

Departments

- Dept. of CSE
- B.Sc in Data Science
- Dept. of EEE
- Dept. of Civil Engineering
- Dept. of Pharmacy
- Dept. of English
- Dept. of EDS
- Dept. of MSJ
- SoBE (BBA, AIS, MBA, EMBA)
- Dept. of Economics
- Dept. of BGE

Admission

- Admission
- Tuition Fees & Waiver
- Admission Requirements
- Admission Test Result
- Admission Procedure
- Admission Notice
- International Students' Admission
- Global Opportunities
- International Collaboration
- FAQ

Important Links

- IBER
- Time Schedule of Shuttle Services
- Student Transportation Service
- Payment Procedure
- Student e-Resources
- Important Contact

Quick Links

- UCAM
- eLMS
- Parent Portal
- Online Classroom Booking
- Degree Verification
- Necessary Forms

- Notice
- News
- Event
- SoBE Old WebSite

United City, Madani Ave, Dhaka 1212 * Privacy Policy * Accessibility Assistance * Copyright * Site Information